[Music]
hi and welcome to this session on what's
new in financial management on reminder
automation my name is Brian Nelson I'm a
program manager in the business Central
team and in this session will focus on
the improvements we've done to
collection management which is a a key
part of any Finance departments in this
release we'll look at the new role
Center we have done for account
receivables administrators we'll look at
the new automation for reminders and
we'll look at how we've improved the
setup of reminder terms so let's just
jump right into it here I am in my new
role Center uh it's called account
receivables
administrator and you can select that
role Center and you'll get a role Center
uh targeted for account receivables
employees and users so the role Center
has all the navigation that you need um
to post the document to new documents in
sales uh of course to the reminders and
it has a a small group of reports that
you often use in connection with account
receivables and
we also added some of the new Excel
reports that might be uh useful to look
into when you're doing collection
management for example the account
receivables report is one we've added
some cues that you know from other role
senders and then we added uh a set of
cues for the reminder
process um cues for knowing how many
have been created how many have been
issued but not paid yet how many have
been issued but not sent yet and then we
have the uh automation uh cues in this
case I've set up three automations we'll
get back to them in a second and we'll
also be notified about uh failures in
these automations so we can take action
and then at the bottom of the page we
have the list with overdue balances for
customers and we have the overdue
invoices so it's easier to to get access
to them let's take a look at the
automation that happens because ideally
you should just be following Along on
your
kpis and see maybe what's happening uh
in terms of reminders being here but the
process it itself should be done uh with
automation so in this company we have
three
automations uh you can combine them or
you can split them up you'll you'll see
that in in a second all of these in this
demo is uh set up as manually executed
automation um pieces but of course you
can set it up so it it always runs
automatically and you don't have to
intervene at
all in this
case I have set up uh an automation for
reminders I can set a a reminder terms
filter that is the main filter when
you're doing reminders in this case I I
just set it for the existing two
reminder terms I have and then you can
set up some
steps that Define how how are they
created in this case there's only one
step and it basically
says create anything it's a create step
and uh include only entries with overdue
amounts so we will create a reminder it
will only contain the overdue amounts it
won't contain a section with the not yet
due open uh
invoices so that's a selection we done
uh we have one
more on issuing once you have created
them you can go and validate them maybe
you want approval for from somebody and
the next step is issuing
reminders for issuing there really isn't
much to do you can set a filter again
this issue reminder step that I've set
up here automation I've set up will only
take the ones that have a reminder terms
filter with domestic so it will leave
the the foreign uh remind us uh for
another badge job or manual
intervention the uh the the action step
here also has a
setup slightly different from the create
because these are some of the options
you can can take replacing posting date
and uh text date or vat date and then
again you can do a a a filter here the
filter is really useful if you have a
lot of reminders for different groups of
of receivables
in that you can set a filter and one of
the filters that are very useful to do
or to include is a reminder automation
code and that means that I will only if
I set a filter for this I would only
pick up the reminders open reminders
that were created with a specific
reminder automation code so I can I can
have multiple jobs generating uh
reminders and I can have issue reminder
jobs that pick groups of
uh these reminders and then issue them
so it can be it can be pretty flexible
tailor we'll leave the filter for for
this one and close it and then we have
the last one once we have issued it we
can choose it choose to send it and with
send we can uh open up the step with
send you can choose to send multiple
times for the same level may be useful
for for the first level you want to be
nice and not bump them up in reminder
levels and and get a little more
professional in your address uh to them
you can uh choose to show um interest
and show amounts that are not due and
whatnot you can lock the interaction and
then um the best option is sent by email
so it doesn't just get printed out and
we've added a new Option so that you can
attach invoices that are referenced in
the reminder you can either have all of
the um invoices like all of the open
ones or only the ones that are overdue
and then include them we'll see that in
in a second it's pretty flexible in the
in the setup you can combine them in one
we could have done one automation here
um and I should probably open this one
again you can see there's a step called
scheduling I didn't show
it so this one is set up for manual
because I want to to to show different
steps uh for you but you can set it up
to be weekly monthly or a custom
schedule and you can even have it like
by day and just whenever there's
something to be processed there will be
a bat job to process it we'll we'll just
flip it back to manual so we are in
control of it I have some customers and
there's overdue balances so it's it's
only fair that we do uh remind
us so easiest way is to go
here and here we have them so let's
let's just start the first badge job in
creating
reminders it only takes a few seconds we
can go in and take a
look you can see it's already completed
you can look at the log
entries and you can drill further down
to it and you can see that two reminders
were created from this Automation and
this could have happened uh
automatically and we'll just go and
check and see what was
created so we have some reminder
two of them created for two different
customers School of Fine Art has the
highest
balance or amount there's a few invoices
there and the next step in in the
reminder process is um is issuing them
now we have just created them so we'll
go into the issue reminder again and
then we'll start this batch job and
again you can go in look at the log
entries but we'll skip that part and
we'll go directly to um to sending them
and we'll start that badge job and again
all of it can be done fully
automatically and then we'll go in and
look we could also go from The List log
entries and we'll take a
look four reminders were emailed and
that is because we created two but as
you saw in the cues on the RO cender I
had already created two and they were
not yet emailed so this batch job
because they were run with the same
automation it will pick them up and and
then send them and that is all right
let's go back and look at the emails
here's an example of the first email I
sent out we'll see how it's created
later uh it has some text it it has a
reference to a date uh and then it has
the the normal content of the email and
then it has the reminder as attachment
in the second round the one the one we
just did with
scent um the
first reminder was due in February I I
was running one from March again so it
picked it up a second time and that
means that the text is a go is going to
be a bit more uh strict short and
professional asking for for prompt
payment and we also included the open
invoices in that email so that they can
go and reference them and and see what
invoices were due in the badge job but
um the difference in these two emails is
from a new capability to tailor the the
emails per level in reminder terms so
we'll take a look at that
now so if you go to reminder terms you
have the the standard
list uh in this uh company we have two
reminder terms one for domestic
customers and one for foreign customers
the domestic reminder terms has a new
setup window window you can turn on the
the new uh feature the new layout uh in
feature management and you'll get to a a
card page that has both the header but
also the the
levels for the header there really isn't
uh that many options you could go and
and tailor emails if you had nothing
else set up I'll skip that part the
interesting part is you're sending out
reminders in at different levels there's
a first reminder kindly asking the
customer to to pay as soon as
conveniently and then the second email
where you remind them that they were
reminded and please pay
fast and then maybe a third reminder
that tells them that now they have to
pay or or the outstanding balance will
be sent to a collection service or
something like that so you have these
levels and you can set it set them up
individually
uh with fees and uh with the due date
calculation for the reminder itself but
you can also click on the customer
communication tab for each level and the
first one for level one that you saw an
email for is that the email is the
reminder itself the attachment will have
begin and ending text within it that
these two text Fields you can use them
to build up a a reminder report but the
email that you sent out will have this
text uh referencing a due date and um
telling the customer if they already
paid they can disregard this email so
that's level one and we'll just close it
for level two they already got one
reminder so um we are telling them
that the the payment was due and we
would appreciate prompt payment and
thank you for your business we don't ask
them to disregard anything because they
already had a reminder that they didn't
react to and you can also include a
subject line in the email so you can
construct or or tailor the emails that
you send out for the different reminder
terms per level so it's it get more
tailor to your business and the tone of
voice and what you're asking for or what
you're including so in that way you have
a better setup for reminders and the
levels for the emails that you send out
you can uh choose to uh to send the
attachment uh along you have automation
to automate all of these steps once you
have your setup and you decided how it
should look like um and be set up in
terms of calculations you can create
automations that will take care of
actually processing this so all there is
for you in collection management is to
sit back and keep an eye on the kpis
because everything will be automated
once you set it up in the coming
releases we'll we'll do a few more
improvements
uh some better overviews and some more
kpis so it's easier to manage collection
management thank you for watching this
session